Inventory to the Records of the Equal Rights Amendment Campaign Archives Project (ERACAP) (1970-1985)
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS(1978-82), 17 linear ft.
  A sample of original video footage for both documentaries has been reformatted and viewing copies are available as digital files and are available online (on-campus access only). See Appendix for descriptions of reformatted footage.
- SERIES I. ERACAP ADMINISTRATION (1981-85), .5 linear ft.
  - Contents (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Project proposal, 1983-84, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Advisory board, 1983, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letters of support, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ERA materials to collect, 1981-83 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Financial materials
    - Expenses, 1983, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sources of funding, 1983, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Grantsmanship Center, 1983, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Tax-exempt status, 1984-85, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence 1983-85, [see also Smith College] (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Memberships, 1982-84 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Equipment and services, 1982-83, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Smith College, 1982-85
      - General, 1982-85 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Alternative Career Conference, April 15-16, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- SERIES II. NATIONAL ORGANIZATION FOR WOMEN AND THE ERA(1970-83)
  - Articles, pamphlets, and reports about the ERA, 1979-80, n.d. ==ERA Countdown Campaign, [see also SERIES III. - Pro-ERA Countdown] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - General, 1981-82, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Celebrity support, 1980-82, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Film, 1968-80, n.d.
      - Film images, 1-643 (Box 2, Folder 1-6)
      - Photo log (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - " Film"
        - "NOW Music Selections:" audiocassette tape, n.d., [digital file available] (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - ==Images, 1974, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - LA Photo Log Images, September 18, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Correspondence, memos, and reports, 1981-82, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Speeches, 1982, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Virginia's ERA Struggle, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Fundraising kit, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Legal Defense and Education Fund
    - General, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Staff members, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Projection Equal Education Rights (PEER), 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Media Project
      - General, 1980-82, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Advertising
        - Equipment, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 3)
        - Outdoor advertising, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - Public Service Announcements (PSAs)
          - Production companies, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
          - Sample scripts, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Notes, 1981, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
        - Radio, 1981-82 (Box 3, Folder 8)
        - Television, 1981-82, [see also Public Service Announcements] (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Artwork, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Conferences and consultations
        - Freestyle evaluation conference, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
        - Michigan Media Project conference, 1980-81 (Box 3, Folder 12)
        - State broadcasting action workshop, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
        - Vanguard Network proposal, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
        - Women in the media study, 1980-83, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 3)
        - Other conferences, 1980-81 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - ERA Awareness Week, 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Pilot Program, 1979-80, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Purchase orders, 1981-82 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Status reports, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Leadership mailing lists, 1979-82, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Marches, rallies, and other events
    - Springfield, IL: Rally, 16 May 1976 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Washington, DC: March, 9 Jul 1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Washington, DC: ERA Inauguration Watch, 20 Jan 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - San Antonio, TX: National Conference, 3-5 Oct 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Utah: Missionary Project, 9 Apr-19 Jul 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - ERA Walkathons, Aug 1981 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Washington, DC: National Conference, 10-12 Oct 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Illinois: Fast for Justice, May 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Capitol March for ERA, 6 June 1982 (Box 4)
      - Kits (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Illinois
        - Contracts (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - General notes (Box 5, Folder 2)
        - Letters to ERA supporters (Box 5, Folder 3)
        - Musicians (Box 5, Folder 4)
        - Material order forms (Box 5, Folder 5)
        - Newspaper clippings (Box 5, Folder 6)
        - Organizational materials (Box 5, Folder 7)
        - Outreach (Box 5, Folder 8)
        - Planning materials (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
        - Recruitment (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Washington, DC: Rally, 30 Jun 1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - PAC/Woman Walkathon, 28 Aug 1982 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Post-ERA response by NOW: Vote out the opposition, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Other state/local activities, 1980-82 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Unidentified ERA events: negatives and proof sheets, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
  - Media Reform Committee
    - General, 1979-81, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Communications technology, 1980, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Federal Communications Commission and discrimination, 1979-81, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Memorabilia
    - Buttons, 1982, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Ribbons, posters, and ERA "business cards," 1977-82, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Stickers, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - General 1981-82, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - NOW Convention, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - NOW Press releases, 1980-82 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Protests
    - Movie: Windows, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Appointment of Rex E. Lee as Solicitor General, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Subject files
    - Draft case/women in the military, 1980-81 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Reagan, Ronald: newspaper clippings, 1980-83 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Reproductive rights, 1980-82, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Other women's issues, 1980-83, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
- SERIES III. WHO WILL PROTECT THE FAMILY? DOCUMENTARY FILES(1974-82, n.d.), [see also SERIES V. -Who Will Protect the Family?]
  - Video logs
    - Raleigh, NC, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Pro/anti-ERA groups and people, 1981 (Box 13)
  - Transcripts, Aug 1981: audiocassettes 1-6 (Box 13, Folder 14-19)
  - Publicity, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Notes and questions, 1981, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Archival visuals (North Carolina), 1981, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - North Carolina contacts, 1981, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Anti-ERA
    - General: articles and newspaper clippings, 1979-82, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - American Family Institute, 1980, n.d. (Box 25)
  - American Life Lobby, 1979-81, n.d., [see also OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 26)
    - Christianity and Politics conference (8-9 May 1981), 1976-81, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Cuddy, Dennis, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - DeVries, Marilyn, 1980, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Family Protection Reporter, 1979-81 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Marshner, Connie, [see also Family Protection Reporter] (Box 7)
    - Moral Majority, 1980-81, n.d., [see also oversize box 12] (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Right Woman, 1979-81, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Schlafly, Phyllis, [see also Stop ERA] (Box 7)
    - Stop ERA, 1980-82 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Other anti-ERA groups, 1979-82, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pro-ERA
    - General: articles, newspaper clippings, and speeches, 1978-81, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Congressional Union, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - ERA America, 1978-80 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
    - ERA Countdown, 30 Jun 1981, [see also SERIES II. NOW and the ERA Countdown Campaign] (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Johnson, Sonya (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - McAllister, Beth, 1981, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Ms. Meeting, 26 May 1981 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - North Carolina Council of Churches, 1981, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Pamphlets, 1978-80, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Shoulder to Shoulder March for the ERA, 2 May 1981 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - New York Times ERA timeline, 1970-82: card file (Box 7a)
  - North Carolina 1981 legislative session
    - Abortion (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Background information, 1979-81, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Day care 1981 legislative session (Box 3)
    - Equal Rights Amendment (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Marital property distribution (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Other bills (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - U.S. Congress
    - Abortion/Human Life Amendment, 1980-81, n.d., [see also Family Protection Act] (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Economic Equity Act, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1978, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Family Protection Act, 1981 (Box 3)
      - CRS Report and Analysis (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Legislation (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Summaries (Box 12)
    - Social Security, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Voting records, 1980-81 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Subjects and statistics
    - Abortion, 1979-81, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Apparel and tobacco industry, 1978-81 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Day care, 1980-81, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Divorce statistics, 1981, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Domestic violence, 1977-81 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Families, 1978-82
      - General, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - National, 1978-82 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Juvenile criminal behavior, 1979-81 (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
  - North Carolina statistics, 1978-81, n.d.
    - Employment, 1978-81 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - General, 1974-81 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Original grids, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Personal Income, 1973-81 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Planned Parenthood: activities and criticisms of, 1980-81, n.d., [see also Sex Education] (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Sex education, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Teenage pregnancy, 1976-81, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Textbooks, 1974-81, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Women, 1975-81, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
- SERIES IV. ERA DEFEAT (1982-84, n.d.), .25 linear ft.
  - Susan Harding articles and papers, 1981-1983 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - ERA essays in OAH newsletter, 1982-83 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - "The Equal Rights Amendment: Anatomy of a Failure," PS, Fall 1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Jennifer Jackman/Tamar Raphael project, 1983-84, [note: most of the audiotapes and transcripts from this project are located in the Women's Rights Collection; see also Correspondence in SERIES I] (Box 11, Folder 4-6)
  - Until Justice is Done: The Fight for the ERA, Spring 1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS(1978-82, n.d.)
  - DVD viewing copies of unedited documentary footage, [These videos are available as digital files and can be viewed on the SSC website (Smith campus only). See Appendix for full descriptions]
    - Who Will Protect the Family?
      - Nos. 1-78 (Box 13)
      - Nos. 79-123 (Box 14)
    - Fighting for the Obvious
      - Nos. 1-44 (Box 14)
      - Nos. 45-72 (Box 15)
  - DVD preservation masters (Box 16-17)
    [CLOSED]
  - Digital Beta tapes (Box 18-28)
  - Original ¾" UMatic videotapes, [For full list of original tapes, contact the SSC] (Box 29-45)
- OVERSIZE MATERIALS
  - American Life Lobby: A.LL. About Issues, Oct 1980-Mar1981 (Box 12)
  - "ERA YES" sign (Box 12)
  - Moral Majority Report (5 issues), 1980-81 (Box 12)
  - Moral Majority: poster, n.d. (Box 12)
  - "The Life and Times of Rosie the Riveter": invitation mock-up, 1981 (Box 12)
  - "Tell Me a Riddle": invitation mock-up, 1981 (Box 12)
  - SAM: Soldier, Sailor, Airman, Marine, Feb 1980: "Women in Combat?...Let's Get Serious" (Box 12)
  - Sash for 1980 ERA march (Box 12)